ユピー！　こら!!
Train and earn money?
んっ？
The Heavens Arena.
こっちだ　ボケ！
Heavens Arena... Yeah, I'll explain later.
「ハギャ様」
So this is where we'll be training...
ウェルフィンとブロヴーダに 疑念を持たせたとも知らずに
I used up all my money on the trip fare.
イカルゴは　パームの姿を求め
We'll have to make more here.
宮殿の地下へと向かっていた
After we disembark, we'll start from zero. Okay, got it.
「サテライトンボ」！
There aren't any conditions here, like there were for the Hunter Exam.
イカルゴは　与えられた 資料でしかパームを知らない
Oh... The higher you go, the more
prize money you earn.
だが　彼女を見つけるまで
This is as good as it gets for those looking
決して宮殿を後にしないとの 覚悟を
to make a living with their fists. Welcome to Heavens Arena.
早くから固めていた 絶対に連れて帰る！
Please fill out this form.
パームは仲間の仲間 つまり仲間だ！
Killua Zoldyck-sama, you are #2054.
俺の仲間だ!!
Gon Freecss-sama, you are #2055.
今　パームは命を懸けている
on the first floor of the arena, so make sure you remember it.
それだけで　イカルゴは 彼女を尊敬できた
Then please go ahead.
助けると決めたから！
Go! Take him out! It's been a while, but the place hasn't changed.
宮殿地下へのエレベーター
Huh? You've been here before?
監視カメラと重量計を内蔵した エレベーターは
Yeah, when I was six. My dad left me here without a penny.
地下へ降りた後 何も乗っていないことを確認し
He said I should reach floor 200
before coming home.
自動的に上へ戻る
It took two years. Two years...
降下は自由に行えるが 上昇時には１名しか乗れず
Sure, he was only six, but it
really took Killua that long?
そして 暗証番号の入力が求められる
If you want to fight people of Hisoka's level, you'll need to go higher.
８桁からなる番号は 一人一人　異なり
Let's hurry. Okay. #1973.
利用者の識別が可能となる
#2055.
番号登録時の身体データと 利用者のデータが
Please enter ring E. #2055! That's me!
著しく異なる場合 即刻　警報が鳴り
I'm getting nervous now.
エレベーターは 簡易の監獄となる
Gon, you got through the
Testing Gate, right? Huh?
１度目の入力ミスで 警告がなされ
In that case... Look at that! It's a little boy!
扉がロックされる
Hey, kid!
再三の誤入力は 警備兵への通報
This is your last chance to run! This ain't a game!
催眠ガス投入後　拘束　拷問
One punch, and he'll fly out of the ring!
すなわち　死を意味する
On the first floor, we appraise
each participant's level.
不審使用者　および その番号の持ち主は
to demonstrate your prowess. Then... Begin!
問答無用で処分されるため 自身の番号は命と等しい
Sorry... I'll end your suffering with one punch.
そうした制約を全く受けずに
You got through the Testing Gate, right? In that case, all you have
to do is push hard.
エレベーターを利用できる 番号の持ち主が
Just push
ビゼフとマルコスである
hard!
人間を含め　さまざまな機密物を 運び込むのに
No way! Yes!
兵士の目がある 車両出入り口よりも
That kid's incredible!
こちらのほうが 都合が良い故の措置だ
He's got some crazy power! When did I become so strong?
何だ!?　この臭いは フラッタの奴　死体安置所にでも 住んでんのか？
Hey, here's another kid who's a beast! Oh?
うっ　うぅ…。
You've already been to the 200th floor?
他には…
And this was a strong performance.
俺より先に降りて行った ブロウの臭いが強いな
Very well. You may go to the 180th floor... Oh, I'll start from the 50th floor. Huh?
クソっ！　微かな臭いが あるには　あるが…
I want to take it easy.
死後　数日経過している フラッタの腐臭が
That's enough!
ウェルフィンの鼻を鈍らせた
Yet another strong kid there!
奴も　フラッタの 「ハギャ様」発言に気付いたか!?
You are permitted to
advance to the 50th floor. Osu!
それとも ブロヴーダもグルか？
The first 200 floors of Heavens Arena
ブロウは　背後で俺を見ていた？
So after someone defeats an
opponent in the 50s, they advance to the 60s. If they lose, then they'd
drop back to the 40s.
だとすると ブロウが賊とグルならば
Oh, so that's how it works. Plus... I've heard that
俺がフラッタの不自然さに 気付いたことに　気付いたはず
after you pass the 100th floor,
you get your own room!
ならば　奴が 先に下へ降りた理由は…
Oh, I forgot to introduce myself. Osu! My name is Zushi! What about you guys?
)
I'm Killua.
下で俺を
I'm Gon. Nice to meet you.
迎え撃つため！
We've arrived at the 50th floor.
フラッタが怪しいのは　確実！
That was really amazing! What are you talking about?
奴を爆破計画の実行犯に 仕立てられれば
You made it up here with one match, too. That's right. No...
ビゼフの俺に対する評価は 確固たるものに！
I still have a long way to go. By the way, which martial arts
discipline do you practice?
ビゼフ!!
I study the Shingen-ryu fighting technique.
ビゼフは!?
School? We don't have one, right? No... What?
マズいな
You're that strong with no training?
奴が　この襲撃で死んでたら
I'm kind of shocked...
計画自体が無意味になる！
I still have so far to go!
フラッタより　まず
Zushi.
ビゼフを見つけないと！
You did well.
よぉ。
Osu! I am honored!
じっちゃん…
Master, your shirt is untucked again.
変わったな
Nice to meet you. I'm Wing.
わしの仕事は　これで終わりじゃ。
I didn't expect to meet other children. Why are you here?
任務以外のことは　何も知らん。
Uh... Well, we want to become stronger.
中の？
Killua's a veteran here. Oh?
言いたいことの 全てをのみ込んで
If you're up here, you must be fairly skilled, but you should pay strict attention to your opponent's body,
as well as your own.
ゼノは闇に紛れた
Osu!
その頃　破壊された 中央大階段の近くでは
One hundred, fifty-two jenny...
姿を現すという
On the 1st floor, win or lose, your reward covers a canned drink.
事前の計画には全くなかった 行動をとったナックルに
But beyond that, a loss gets you nothing.
メレオロンとシュートが
A win over an opponent in the 50s
nets you fifty thousand. Fifty thousand...
息をのんでいた
That's a lot. In the 100s, I think wins are worth a million.
来いや!!
Didn't you make it to floor 200
when you were here before?
来いや!!
How much do you get for
winning on the 200th floor? Well... I don't really know, because I quit once I reached 200.
なるほど…　こっちは　お前のか。
But when I was winning in the 190s, I had around two hundred million, total. T-Two hundred million... Where's that money now?
んっ！ 数が増えた？
Spent it all on snacks! Two hundred million on snacks, in four years? What kind of snacks are these?
んっ？
We didn't take any damage in the last fight, so they'll probably assign us
another match today.
んっ？
Well, these opponents should be a cinch.
俺の攻撃が効かねえ 何だ？　こいつは。
Really? Killua-san! You're too loud...
フッ。
#2054, Killua-sama.
逃げるな！　答えろ！ こいつは　何だ！
I'm already up. And #1963, Zushi-sama. What?
誰が教えるか！
Please head to arena A, on the 57th floor. Oh.
バカ野郎が！
Osu! I shall give it my best.
知りたきゃ捕まえろってんだ！
Sure. Well, you can't win them all.
くっ…。
Better luck next time.
うお！
I'll head out. Yeah. Good luck, guys.
I'll wait for you above. Uh-huh...
完全に１人でやる気だ ナックルの奴！
He really didn't have to be so blunt...
ナックルに　たどり着くなんて 俺には無理！
Okay, everyone! The event you've all been waiting for!
ならば！
We have a unique match-up for you!
急ぎ過ぎず　遅過ぎず
Two young boys, fighting it out!
なるべく 酸素消費を少なく歩け！
However, you don't want to
underestimate them! Both had strong showings
in their first rounds!
ハァ　ハァ…。
They both advanced directly to the 50s! We will now replay
あっ。
Killua defeated his opponent in a flash! One chop was all it took to knock him out!
うっ！　うっ…。
Meanwhile, Zushi used martial arts
うっ…。 気を… 失うわけには　いかない
to punish his opponent, scoring a flawless knockout
of a 200-plus kilogram giant!
気絶したら
Okay, everyone! Are you ready to press
your gamble switches?
「ホテル・ラフレシア」は 解除されてしまう…
In that case, switch on!
ほんの…　わずかな傷でも
All bets are in, and the odds favor Zushi!
決して無駄ではないはず…
Perhaps his martial arts
knowledge gives him an edge?
うぅ…　うっ…。
This match will consist of three,
three-minute rounds, decided by the points and knockout system! Begin!
俺は　まだ…
I see.
やれる…。
His stance leaves few openings.
俺は　まだ…。
He's trained long and hard
to master that stance. But he has no chance against me.
くっ…。
Wow... Killua is boldly walking toward his opponent!
Sorry. But I'm sticking to one chop per
match until I reach the 150s.
くっ…。
Clean hit!
できねえ…　言えねえ！
Amazing! Killua has knocked out another
opponent with only a single chop!
これ以上　シュートに 「頑張れ！」なんて！
A clean hit and a knockdown
get him 2 points. As you already know, under the
points and knockout system, there are clean hits, critical hits,
and knockdowns.
俺が　今やるべきこと！
Superb attacks count as "clean hits,"
worth one point apiece. Unusually superb attacks
くっ！
are classified as "critical hits,"
worth two points.
シュートを 助けることじゃねえ！
Knocking down your opponent
earns you one point.
他のメンバーを 俺の能力で助け １秒でも早く 任務を成功させること！
After amassing ten points, you are
awarded a technical knockout. Of course, if your opponent cannot
continue to fight after one hit, you win due to a knockout!
生きろよ！　シュート!!
That chop ended the fight, stupid. Can you fight?
死ぬな!!
Yes, I'm okay!
誰もいない
He's taken another hit!
慌てるな　よく周りを見て
But he's already standing up! If you stand before the referee reaches you, your opponent isn't awarded the point.
万が一　見つかっても まだ俺はアリの側で通せる！
Tsk. Not bad. So the same attack won't
work twice against you.
…が
But something's wrong.
相手次第では　言い訳が 通じねえことだってある！
That attack was strong enough that a graze
プハ。
should have rendered him unconscious.
「パーフェクトプラン」解除！
Unbelievable...
スハ　スハ。
He has dominating power and speed! At this rate, I won't stand a chance!
スゥ！
I have to...
よし　発動！
try it!
だとすると　あとは
Oh! What's happening? Killua has backed away!
ゴンとキルアしかいない！
Zushi!
こいつは厄介！ 軍団長いちの懐疑主義者
interrupted the fight, but let's get started again!
疑われたら最後 死ぬまで信用されねえ！
Oh, Killua! Over here!
息が　もう持たねえ… 逃げるか？
How about you? It took you a while to get here.
どっちへ？
Yeah, I ran into a little trouble.
奴が同じほうへ来たら？
Then Zushi was pretty strong. No, not at all.
やり過ごすか？
He has potential. One day, he'll be strong.
息は持つか!?
But right now, he's just target practice for me. His punches were weak...
無理だ！　持たねえ！
But I couldn't defeat him.
限界!! くっ！
Huh? I received the TKO from points, but I couldn't knock him out.
大きく素早く吐いて すぐ吸うしかねえ！
When he changed his stance, his aura reminded me of my brother's.
「パーフェクトプラン」解除！ ハァ！
I don't know what it was,
but it felt dangerous.
んっ!?
It must be some kind of technique.
そして　吸え！　発動！
His master called it "Ren."
今　一瞬　気配がした
Forgive me, Master! I thought I made myself clear, Zushi.
くっ…
My opponent was so strong, I couldn't help myself...
敵か!?
Sure. Wanting to win is good.
ウェルフィンの能力は 本人の性格を色濃く投影し
But your true goal lies beyond this.
疑い深く　狡猾な力を備えていた
At this tower's top floor. Focus too much on simply winning a fight, and you reduce your own potential.
建物の後ろに隠れている奴！ いるならば　３つ数えるうちに 投降し　出て来い！
Osu! You must be prepared to lose a
thousand times while you're here. Osu! So he isn't supposed
さもないと　攻撃を開始する！
to use Ren until he reaches the top floor?
３！
The strongest fighters are at the top, right?
２！
Gon, change in plans.
１！
Huh? I'm aiming to reach the top floor!
いない…　気のせいか？
Killua defeats another opponent
with one chop! A knockout!
ウェルフィンの 「ミサイルマン」は 対象者を定め 弾となる質問　命令を込め
Oh! In the other arena, Gon has knocked out another opponent with a single push!
偽った者　逆らった者がいた場合
Each of them has won six
consecutive matches
攻撃が開始される ウェルフィンが 気配を察した時
over the past three days, to reach the 100s without a scratch!
メレオロンは　すでに その場を離れていた
Killua's chop.
もしも　メレオロンが　その場に とどまっていたならば ウェルフィンが 意識できないにかかわらず
And Gon's push. How far will they be able to go?
攻撃は成立していたが 対象者に該当しなかったため 不発に終わった
And who is going to be able to stop them?
「ミサイルマン」は 一度　発動すれば 命中するまで対象者を追い続け
Yay! A private room!
その攻撃が命中して 生きている者はいない
We won't have to worry about
money and lodging anymore. I wouldn't be too sure about that.
しかし ウェルフィンは自分の能力を
If you drop below the 100s, you have to
check out of this room.
無敵だとは思っていなかった
A world of difference separates making it
能力は　あくまでも 交渉の道具の一つ
to the 100s and staying in the 100s.
ウェルフィンにとっては
The 100th floor is like a ceiling. A ceiling?
自分の能力さえも 疑う対象であり
Once you pass it, you get special treatment.
影の王を目指すのも 真の王になった場合に
So everyone focuses on holding their spot.
疑うべきものの量が
Some people will do anything it takes
己の許容を 超えているからにすぎない
to stay in the 100s.
やはり気のせい？
You can waste a lot of time on them.
いや　しかし…
Be careful, Gon. Yeah.
無香性の消臭剤の香り
Gon wins another match
with a single push!
フン！ 俺の鼻は　ごまかせねえぜ！
Guess I didn't need to worry about him.
消臭剤を使うあたり 確実に俺を警戒している
Your prize money has been deposited
into the specified account.
もう　アリの中に
You were right...
裏切り者がいるのは 間違いない！
I've never seen so many zeros before...
フラッタ以外にも　いるのか？ 恐らく　答えはイエス！
And just a week ago, I was totally broke.
そして 俺は　そいつを知っている！
I'm a little annoyed. Huh?
だからこそ そいつは　においを消した！ 誰だ？
My first time here, it took me two months to reach floor 150.
俺と戦う気は　ない？
Meanwhile, you're breezing through. But you were only six back then.
いつでも　やれるから？
Well, that's true...
俺は　俺は…
I wonder what that Ren you sensed could have been.
俺は　このまま アリの側でいいのか？
Maybe if we fight opponents higher up...
俺が　今やるべきことは
Or wouldn't it be faster to just ask Zushi?
本当にビゼフを探すことか？
Ren is one of the four major principles.
ウェルフィンが　自らの目的に 疑問を感じ始めていた頃
The four major principles for
disciplining your mind and body. Fundamental to every martial art! You must know "Ten," learn "Zetsu,"
ゴンとキルアは　ついに
Because it's related to the secret
behind my brother's power.
カイトの敵である ネフェルピトーを
Then, your brother is able to use Nen?
その視線の先に捉えていた
I need to know what Nen
and Ren even mean! I'll agree to the full learning process
rather than a quick explanation!